# **O**maima

# **AL-Samsami**



### Contact



Muscat, Oman



+968-92640731



102310@oq.com

#### Languages

Arabic English

#### **Education**

### -(2017- 2021) Master of Environmental Engineering

College of Engineering, Sultan Qaboos University, Sultanate of Oman, (GPA: 3.8/4.0). Master Thesis was bout properities and estimate energy of both Muscat MSW & WWTS.

### -(2010 -2015) Bachelor of Chemical & Process Engineering

College of Engineering, Sultan Qaboos University, Sultanate of Oman, (GPA: 3.2/4.0)

#### -(2009-2010) Diploma Certificate

Um Hakeem School. Sultanate of Oman, AL-Awabi, Overall grade: 97.4%

# **Summary**

An experienced engineer in oil and gas field with over 8 years of experience in process Continuous improvement, digitalization projects implementation, data modeling & analytics, global benchmarking studies, Power BI dashboard developments. A fast learner and eager to deliver out-of-the-box solutions. At OQ, I developed and improved many company performances dashboards that raise up data quality and save hundreds working hours, and key member of operation improvements program that generate 6+ Mn USD saving in its first year (2019). I Led many digitalization initiatives implantations and developed many insightful dashboards for organization leaders.

# Skill Highlights

- Proficient in Office 365
   Applications
- Professional in Power BI reports and Dashboard devlopments
- Skilled in Power Apps and Flow Automate
- Strong communication and presentation skills for both technical and non-technical stakeholders.
- Skilled in Data managmnae & Report automation

- Creative thinker & Professional researcher
- Proficient in Process Information Book, Process Information vision and Process Information Assets Frame (PI AF) Performance Improvement Processes & Benchmarking Studies
- Excellent analytical and problemsolving skills with a keen attention to detail.
- Knowledge of data management practices

# **Experience**

# Sr. Specialist Data Warehouse&Report.Managments (01st Mar 2023 – Till Date) Core Responsibilities:

- Lead transformation of manual reports to Power BI & Full development of HSE Data Power BI Reports & Dashboard
- Improve reporting process to be more lean and save time for analysis

# **Sr Specialist Project Technology & Digitization (01**st **Jan 2021–01**st **Mar 2023)** Core Responsibilities:

- Work with Digitalization Transformation owner to establish a Digitalization Transformation plan for mega projects leaders.
- Develop many insightful performance dashboards in Power Bi Platform.
- Focal point for supporting any project related to IT data management tool, or tool that will support effective Mega Projects data integration or data analytical.
- Lead implementation of new data managment systems like auomated lesson learnt workflows and centralized database. Led implementation of new technologies like remote support and UAV inspection projects.

### Performance Improvement & Digitalization Engineer (15 Jul 2018 - 01st Jan 2021)

OQ, Muscat/Suhar, Oman

Core Responsibilities:

• Utilize knowledge of data analysis techniques, and visualization tools to extract meaningful insights from technical data, identify trends, and proactively address potential risks. To provide technical management insight of all operational asset's performance indicators by effectively analyzing and interpreting data.

# **Experience**

- Develop and implement data-driven strategiese. dveloping and improving company operational performance reports and dashboards.
- Building technical monitoring dashboards that help in improving company performance in excel and PI vision mainly for operation
- Coordinator of many important global benchmarking studies like Solomon and site personnel index study (SPI).
- Develop high-quality real-time dashboards for product quality the speed up and ease quality parameter monitoring and decrease offspec products.

# Special Assignment in Operation Continuous Improvement Program (Lean) (01st Feb 2019 – 01st Jan 2021)

OQ, Muscat/Suhar, Oman Core Responsibilities:

- Find the best performance measurement indicator and ways of calculations
- Manage the new initiatives implementations (Design input and monitoring dashboards, engagements workshops, trained people how to use the tools and then handover the tool to operation)
- Continue improvement of the processes and effectives of the tools and meeting toward value maximization
- Program create USD +6 Mn in the first year of the implementation.

### Performance Analyst (1st Mar 2018 – 15th Jul 2018)

Orpic, Muscat, Oman

Core Responsibilities:

- Fully responsible of monitoring, measuring, tracking and reporting all company key performance indicators (KPIs).
- Developed one KPI library of all company KPI as data base that shift the quality of KPI selection, measurements and monitoring to new advance stage and save +50 monthly working hours.
- Develop new KPIs scorecards monitoring dashboareds.

### Corporate Planning Officer (15<sup>th</sup> Nov 2015 – 1<sup>st</sup> Mach 2018)

Orpic, Muscat, Oman

Core Responsibilities:

- Automate all company KPI calculations formula which increase calculations accuracy and reduce working times form days to hours
- Deliver the company 5-Year Business Plan planning cycle successfully for the year of 2017
- Handled the company executive team reports about all performance aspects progress on daily, weekly & monthly basis.
- Accountable of company corporate and functions KPIs monitoring and reporting.

## **Certificates**

- Power BI Certificate
- Analyzing PI System Data (Oct 2019)
- Visualizing PI System Data with PI (Dec 2019)
- Process Information Asset Framework (PI-AF) (Apr 2019)
- Solomon Data Analysis (Nov 2019)
- Wastewater Treatment Processes (Jul 2018)
- Stakeholder Engagement (Apr 2018)
- KPI management (Apr 2017)

# **Other Participations**

- 2019 PI World conference in Sweden
- 4th ISA Oman Conference-2020
- Department Fire warden-2018
- Active member in South Al-Batinah "Free of Illiteracy Program" (2008).

### References

Prof. Mahad Baawan-Department of Civil & Architecture Engineering,
Sultan Qaboos University Tel: + (968) 24142543, Fax No.: 24141354 E-mail: msab@squ.edu.om

Juma AL MASKARI (Team Leader Performance Improvement & Digitalization at OQ)— Technical Service Function, Muscat Tel: + (968) 22106616, E-mail: juma.almaskari@oq.com